你们好，我的名字是布莱恩-道格拉斯
what's up y'all my name is Brian Douglas
open sauce的创始人和维护者
founder maintainer of open sauce
这将会是关于
it's gonna be talking about
洞察力和开放马的贡献
insights and opens horse contribution
所以让我继续分享我的屏幕
so let me go ahead and share my screen
并直接跳入
and jump right in
因此，去年我们有机会实际交谈
so last year we had the opportunity to actually talk
我们去年有机会和Avenue讨论小麦代表的2点发射问题。
to avenue about wheat rep for the 2 point launch
在那次谈话之后，我改变了
and after that conversation I switched
我们最终将所有的开放式酱料转为小麦
we ended up switching all of open sauce into wheat
所以非常高兴能成为这个社区的一部分
so super happy to be a part of this community
做贡献
to be contributing
对上游的贡献不大
not too much contributing upstream
但希望很快，因为那是我们的目标所在
but hopefully soon because that's where our goal is
事实上，开放源代码的贡献很好，但
actually fine open source contributions but
当我提到
when I mentioned
我很快就会去
I'm going to go quickly
给它一个快速的演示，我的现场演讲将是什么？
to give it a quick demo of what my floor talk will be
这将是一种像偷袭或小吃
this would be sort of like a sneak or a snack
的开放酱料的比萨饼
of open sauce that pizza
是的，我将直接跳入
and yeah I'll jump right in
是的
yeah
所以open sauce是开源的智能仪表板
so open sauce is open source intelligence dashboard
我们实际上一直在为git仓库编制索引
we're actually we've been indexing git repos
并在此基础上提供洞察力
and providing insights on top of that
所以我们一直在搞这个
so we've been messing around this
几乎整整一年了
for pretty much all year
我一直在全职工作
I've been working on this full time
在过去的三个月里
for the past 3 months
真的很高兴与大家分享
and really happy to share
我们终于有了一个网址，就是opensasa的insights。
finally we have a url which is insights at opensasa
披萨，这将是我们所有的洞察力
pizza this will be the home for all of our insights
和仪表盘
and dashboards
暂时的
for the time being
将会支持十月的节日
will be supporting October fest
通过对所有这些存储库的审查和
by vincites on all those repositories and
识别诸如垃圾邮件和贡献的东西
identify things like spam and contribution
所以一定要看一下
so definitely check it out
但我想在这里真正开始的阶段
but I wanted to really to start the stage here
真正的快速和谈论像github提供的东西
real quick and talk about like what github offers
而不是说我们想直接竞争什么
and not that what we're trying to compete directly to
我们希望更多的人能够贡献
get up we want more people to contribute
开源和利用github
open source and leverage github
但我想指出的是，github实际上有
but I do want to point out that github actually has
一些缺失的部分
some missing pieces
至少是这个功能的一部分
at least a part of this feature
所以，当你进入内部的时候，点击github
so when you go to the insides tap on github
这就是它的样子
this is what it looks like
这是为V
this is for v
而这是所有的贡献
and this is all the contribution
在过去的4个月里
in the last actually 4 months
实际上是5个月，在这一点上我的计算是错误的
actually 5 months at this point my math is off
最大的前两名贡献者是苏菲和巴托克
and the biggest top 2 contributors is Sophie and batok
和这个人指出，因为很多人不知道。
and this one on the point that out because a
很多人都不知道
lot of people don't know
你实际上可以
you could actually
抓取日历上的一个部分
grab just like one section of the calendar
然后找到那段时间的贡献
then find contributions for that time
很多时候，当你看到捐款时
a lot of times when you look at contributions
它告诉你自成立以来的无限期。
it tells you indefinitely since the inception
有时你只想知道谁在捐款
and sometimes you just want to know who's contributing
我们想用开放的酱汁来回答这个问题
recently we want to answer that question in open sauce
很容易回答这个问题
pretty easily
另一件事是像
the other thing is like
你并没有真正得到
you don't really get
对实际发生的事情的洞察力
insights on what actually is happening
你得到的是布洛姆，你看起来像分布和
you get blobs and you look like distribution and
活动
activity
正如你所看到的，安东尼在五月初有一个很大的推动力
as you see Anthony had a big push earlier in may
蓝V
blue v
有一段时间的贡献是全面的
contribution across the board for a while
看到这个很好
and it's good to see this
因为你可以看到谁在
because you can see who's
你可以看到谁是活跃的，如果你想联系谁
active and who to reach out to if you want to
在某些事情上得到解脱或解封
get unstuck or unblocked on certain things
但开放的酱汁，就像我们相信的那样，它
but open sauce like we believe that it
你不应该拥有它
you shouldn't have it
要知道秘密的酱汁，以便作出贡献
to know the secret sauce in order to contribute
就像我们想分享那个秘密酱汁
like we want to share that secret sauce
这就是我们在我们的平台上一直在做的事情
and that's what we've been doing with our platform
所以这也是同样的日历
and so this is the same calendar
它只是翻转
it's just flip
所以今天是在左边
so today's on the left
我们要把它转回右边
we're going to switch it back to the right
但无论如何，这是所有捐款的分布
but anyway this is distribution of all contribution
在过去35天里
in the last 35 days
因为很多时候
because a lot of times
当你想看看一个项目是否活跃时
when you want to see if a project is active
或者看看谁在社区里
or see who's around in the community
你想看看最近有谁在做贡献
you want to look like who's been contributing recently
这就是这个。
and that's what this is
而这些都是不良追求的代表
and these are representations of poor quest
但从一开始
but right off the bat
你可以看到在第一个象限，你有7天的时间
you could see in the first quadrant you have 7 days
是过去的7天
is the last 7 days
而且你已经可以看到
and already you can see
有一个人苏菲
there's one person Sophie
从其他人中脱颖而出
who's sticking out from the rest
如果它再高一点
and if it was any higher
我们可能会担心
we'd probably be concerned about
巴士因素或知识转移
bus factor or knowledge transfer
但这仍然是好的，低于50%的标准。
but this is it's still okay below the 50 percent Mark
但我想说的是
but what I want to
指出的是，实际上说这个分配
point out is that actually saying this distribution
现在你有一个想法，比如
now you have an idea of like
整个团队或跨社区发生了什么？
across a team or crossing community what's happening
但我们仍然处于与github相同的位置
but we're still in the same position as github
在那里你无法看到所有的内容
where you can't actually see all this context
除非你打开一堆标签或一堆PRS
unless you open a bunch of tabs or a bunch of prs
来查看什么人对什么版本有贡献
to see what kind of contributed to what release
所以有了open sauce，我们想让这一切变得更简单
so with open sauce we want to make this easier
这里有所有
here's all
在过去35天里发生的贡献
contributions that are happening in the last 35 days
或特别是Sofi
or particularly sofi
所以它不仅仅是一个PR
so it's not just one PR
它是多个PR，多个提交
it's multiple PR multiple commits
我们看到最上面的一个7 36
and we see like the top one 7 36
这就是右上角有多少行被改变了
that's how many lines have changed up in the top right
所以看起来像是有一些依赖关系链
so looks like there was some dependency chain
所以可能是软件包的锁文件
so like maybe the package lock file
我之前并没有研究过这个问题，但是
I didn't look into this actually prior but
有很多的
there's a lot of
依赖关系的变化
changes in dependencies
这就是为什么他从其他人中脱颖而出的原因
which is why he's standing out from the rest
但好消息是
but the good news is
大多数人的贡献大小都是一样的
most people have the same sort of size contributions
事情很容易被跟踪和审查，所以
things are easily tracked and reviewed so
所以很难总是审查一个大的PR
it's hard always review a large PR
我们能够做的另一件事是，实际上
the other thing that we were able to do is actually
基于索引的在线
index based online
嗯，所以我们可以做一些启发式的工作，确定
um so we can do some heuristics and identifying
是否是一个维护性的变化
whether it is a maintenance change
所以，如果它是一个软件包锁文件
so if it is a package lock file
还是说它实际上是新的代码
or if it's actually new code
在项目中添加的新功能
new features added to the project
还是只是重构
or if it's just refactoring
所以文件仍然是一样的
so files are still the same
但东西被移来移去的功能和移动
but things are moved around functions and moved around
所以
so
识别像这样的东西，但是
identify things like this mamenta circle that but
识别这种类型的东西
identify that type of stuff
让我们更容易知道哪些类型的贡献者
makes it easier to know what types of contributors
是临时贡献者还是积极贡献者
are the casual contributors or the active contributors
他们是维护者吗？
are they maintainers
我们希望能通过这个洞察力
there's a things that we're hoping to
通过这种洞察力开始浮出水面
start surfacing through this insight
所以我们才刚刚开始
so we'rejust getting started
期待着更多我们想做的事情。
looking forward to ship way more we want to do
我们想超越绿色方块，并确定
we want to go past just green squares and identify
贡献的机会
opportunity for contribution
所以，如果你有兴趣
so if you're interested in
聊一聊你的项目
chatting more about your project
或如果你有任何
or if you have any
在生态系统中的项目，我们很愿意与您交谈
projects in the ecosystem we would love the chat
并看看我们是否能为你提供见解
and see if we can provide insights for you
所以，请查看完整的谈话内容，并且是
so check out the full talk and yeah
享受节目的其余部分
enjoy the rest of the show